Francisco Solis

Full Stack Web Developer:

Junction City, Ks United States 949-566-4036

solis221995@yahoo.com | https://github.com/fpsolis219

Profile:

A veteran with heavy equipment experience and now full stack web developer graduate @ LEARN ACADEMY with newly acquired skills in writing different coding languages such as Javascript, HTML ,CSS and Ruby. Additional to these skills, can utilize them with frameworks such as ReactJS and Ruby on Rails to create applications and understanding of databases such as PostgreSQL and Active Record. Currently in a transition to seek employment opportunities that can provide mentorship and utilize my skillset to benefit their company.

Technical Skills:

• Coding Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, Postman, PostgreSQL, SQL

• Frameworks: ReactJS, Ruby on Rails

• Version Control: Github

Soft Skills:

- Planning/Project Management
- Active listening
- Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving

Projects: All Project resource can be found on Github https://github.com/fpsolis219

Text Based Game- This project demonstrates my ability to use Ruby to create a collective user interaction and my understanding of the IRB console. A very creative storytelling and fun user interaction project!

Pig Latin Project- This Project was built using JavaScript functionality to create a Pig Latin translator with mob programming practice. A very complicated yet the first step into my introduction of react. **Tic-Tac-Toe-** This project is created using ReactJS and Demonstrates the concept of importing, usestates, JSX, etc.

Block Game- A Generic yet simple practice concept on the use of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript functionality.

Experience:

LEARN Academy: STUDENT, San Diego, Ca Aug, 2022 - Nov, 2022

• Completed 480 + hours of direct coding experience in an intensive web development bootcamp.

- Gained proficiency in building JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, and CSS
- Practiced coding languages and TDD through front-end frameworks in ReactJS and full-stack Ruby on Rails applications, complete with databases.
- Continuing practice on effective communication and cooperation through pair and mob programming projects with teammates.

Midwest Concrete Construction: Heavy Equipment Operator Manhattan KS, Feb, 2022 - May, 2022

• Worked in a rock quarry as a heavy equipment operator with the responsibility of managing the entire plant and distributing material goods to customers.

Waste Management: Heavy Equipment Operator Topeka, KS, Aug, 2021 - Feb, 2022

Heavy equipment operator in landfill site owned by waste management.

Roles consist of operating and alternating various pieces of machinery such as:

- Dump truck
- Dozer
- Excavator
- Water truck
- Compactor
- Backhoe
- Skid steer

Capable of loading and unloading material and transporting to specific locations of landfill.

Excavating material from the earth to machinery.

Pushing and covering material as well compacting to proper grade level.

Capable of operating in harsh weather environments.

United States Army: Soldier/Heavy Equipment Operator Fort Leonard Wood, MI Jan, 2015-Apr, 2022

- In Addition to basic training, completed 10 weeks of advanced individual training (AIT) to learn how to operate various types of Heavy Equipment.
- Gained the skills to run equipment such as: Loader, Excavator, Backhoe, Scraper, Dozer, Dump Truck, Grader.
- Proficient in preventing defects on heavy machinery with maintenance checks and services.
- Learned skills to work independently and as a team to increase productivity on construction projects.
- Continued training and skills into an assigned duty station.
- Transferred skills to different employment opportunities post military service.

Education:

- LEARN Academy: , San Diego, Ca Aug, 2022 Nov, 2022
- United States Army: Fort Leonard Wood, MI Jan, 2016-Apr, 2016
- University of Maryland, University College: Adelphi, Md Mar, 2018 Dec, 2018